<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="5" auto_indent="NO">
	<item>		<name>Monster Hunter's Pack</name>		<type>G</type>		<weight>48.5</weight>		<text>Includes:</text>		<text>	&#8226; a chest</text>		<text>	&#8226; a crowbar</text>		<text>	&#8226; a hammer</text>		<text>	&#8226; three wooden stakes</text>		<text>	&#8226; a holy symbol</text>		<text>	&#8226; a flask of holy water</text>		<text>	&#8226; a set of manacles</text>		<text>	&#8226; a steel mirror</text>		<text>	&#8226; a flask of oil</text>		<text>	&#8226; a tinderbox</text>		<text>	&#8226; 3 torches</text>		<text />		<text>Cost: 33 gp</text>		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 209</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Tome of Strahd</name>		<type>G</type>		<weight>5</weight>		<text>The Tome of Strahd is an ancient work penned by Strahd, a tragic tale of how he came to his fallen state. The book is bound in a thick leather cover with steel hinges and fastenings. The pages are of parchment and very brittle. Most of the book is written in the curious shorthand that only Strahd employs. Stains and age have made most of the work illegible, but several paragraphs remain intact.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 221</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Blood Spear</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>Kavan was a ruthless chieftain whose tribe lived in the Balinok Mountains centuries before the arrival of Strahd von Zarovich. Although he was very much alive, Kavan had some traits in common with vampires: he slept during the day and hunted at night, he drank the blood of his prey, and he lived underground. In battle, he wielded a spear stained with blood. His was the first blood spear, a weapon that drains life from those it kills and transfers that life to its wielder, imbuing that individual with the stamina to keep fighting.</text>		<text>	When you hit with a melee attack using this magic spear and reduce the target to 0 hit points, you gain 2d6 temporary hit points.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, spear</text>		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 221</text>		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>T,V</property>		<range>20/60</range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Dawnbringer</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement by a creature of non-evil alignment)</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>Lost for ages in the Underdark, Dawnbringer appears to be a gilded longsword hilt.  While grasping the hilt, you can use a bonus action to make a blade of pure radiance spring from the hilt, or cause the blade to disappear. Dawnbringer has all the properties of a sun blade: you gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, which deals radiant damage instead of slashing damage. When you hit an undead with it, that target takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage.</text>		<text>	The sword's luminous blade emits bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. The light is sunlight. While the blade persists, you can use an action to expand or reduce its radius of bright and dim light by 5 feet each, to a maximum of 30 feet each or a minimum of 10 feet each. </text>		<text>	While holding the weapon, you an use an action to touch a creature with the blade and cast lesser restoration on that creature. Once used. this ability can't be used again until the next dawn. </text>		<text>	Sentience: Dawnbringer is a sentient neutral good weapon with an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 15, and a Charisma of 14. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet. </text>		<text>	The sword can speak, read, and understand Common, and it can communicate with its wielder telepathically. Its voice is kind and feminine. It knows every language you know while you're attuned to it. </text>		<text>	Personality: Forged by ancient sun worshipers, Dawnbringer is meant to bring light into darkness and to fight creatures of darkness. It is kind and compassionate to those in need, but fierce and destructive to its enemies. </text>		<text>	Long years last in darkness have made Dawnbringer frightened of both the dark and abandonment. It prefers that its blade always be present and shedding light in areas of darkness, and it strongly resists being parted from its wielder for any length of time.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, longsword, shortsword</text>		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 222</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>V, F</property>		<range></range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Dragontooth Dagger</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare</detail>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>A dagger fashioned from the tooth of a dragon. While the blade is obviously a fang or predator's tooth, the handle is leather wrapped around the root of the tooth, and there is no crossguard.</text>		<text>	You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls you make with this weapon. On a hit with this weapon, the target takes an extra 1d6 acid damage.</text>		<text>	Draconic Potency: Against enemies of the Cult of the Dragon, the dagger's bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls increases to  2, and the extra acid damage increases to 2d6.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, dagger</text>		<text>Source: The Rise of Tiamat p. 94</text>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>F,L,T</property>		<range>20/60</range>		<roll>1d6</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Drown</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>4</weight>		<text>A steel trident decorated with bronze barnacles along the upper part of its haft, Drown has a sea-green jewel just below the tines and a silver shell at the end of its haft. It floats on the surface if dropped onto water, and it floats in place if it is released underwater. The trident is always cool to the touch, and it is immune to any damage due to exposure to water. Drown contains a spark of Olhydra, the Princess of Evil Water.</text>		<text>	You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. When you hit with it, the targets takes an extra 1d8 cold damage.</text>		<text>	Water Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Drown:</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can speak Aquan fluently.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You have resistance to cold damage.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on a water elemental. Once you have done so, Drown can't be used this way again until the next dawn. </text>		<text>	Tears of Endless Anguish: While inside a water node, you can perform a ritual called the Tears of Endless Anguish, using Drown to create a devastation orb of water (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Drown can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn. </text>		<text>	Flaw: Drown makes its wielder covetous. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I demand and deserve the largest share of the spoils, and I refuse to part with anything that's mine." In addition, if you are attuned to Drown for 24 consecutive hours, barnacles form on your skin. The barnacles can be removed with a greater restoration spell or similar magic, but not while you are attuned to the weapon.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, trident</text>		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 224</text>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>T,V</property>		<range>20/60</range>		<roll>1d8</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Gurt's Greataxe</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>325</weight>		<text>In the Year of the Icy Axe (123 DR), the frost giant lord Gurt fell to Uthgar Gardolfsson &#8212; leader of the folk who would become the Uthgardt barbarians-in a battle that marked the ascendance of humankind over the giants in the Dessarin Valley. Gurt's greataxe was buried in Morgur's Mound until it was unearthed and brought back to Waterdeep. After laying in the city's vaults for decades, the axe was given to Harshnag, a frost giant adventurer, in recognition of his service to Waterdeep. Uthgardt barbarians recognize the weapon on sight and attack any giant that wields it. </text>		<text>	You gain a +l bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It is sized for a giant, weighs 325 pounds, and deals 3d12 slashing damage on a hit, plus an extra 2d12 slashing damage if the target is human. The axe sheds light as a torch when the temperature around it drops below O degrees Fahrenheit. The light can't be shut off in these conditions. As an action, you can cast a version of the heat metal spell (save DC 13) that deals cold damage instead of fire damage. Once this power is used, it can't be used again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.  When not attacking, you may hold the weapon in one hand.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, greataxe</text>		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 236</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>3d12</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>H,2H</property>		<range></range>		<roll>2d12</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Hazirawn</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>6</weight>		<text>A sentient (neutral evil) greatsword, Hazirawn is capable of speech in Common and Netherese. Even if you aren't attuned to the sword, you gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls and damage rolls made with this weapon. If you are attuned to Hazirawn, you deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage when you hit with the weapon.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Increased Potency: While you are attuned to this weapon, its bonus on attack rolls and damage rolls increases to +2, and a hit deals an extra 2d6 necrotic damage (instead of 1d6)</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Spells: Hazirawn has 4 charges to cast spells. As long as the sword is attuned to you and you are holding it in your hand, you can cast detect magic (1 charge), detect evil and good (1 charge), or detect thoughts (2 charges). Each night at midnight, Hazirawn regains 1d4 expended charges.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Wounding: While you are attuned to the weapon, any creature that you hit with Hazirawn can't regain hit points for 1 minute. The target can make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending this effect early on a success.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.  When not attacking, you may hold the weapon in one hand.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, greatsword</text>		<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen p. 94</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>H, 2H</property>		<range></range>		<roll>1d6</roll>		<roll>2d6</roll>		<roll>1d4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Hew</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>unique</detail>		<weight>4</weight>		<text>Hew is a +1 battleaxe that deals maximum damage when the wielder hits a plant creature or an object made of wood.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, battleaxe</text>		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver, p. 33</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>V</property>		<range></range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Ironfang</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>2</weight>		<text>A war pick forged from a single piece of iron, Ironfang has a fang-like head inscribed with ancient runes. The pick is heavy in the hand, but when the wielder swings the pick in anger, the weapon seems almost weightless. This weapon is immune to any form of rust, acid, or corrosion &#8212; nothing seems to mark it. Ironfang contains a spark of Ogremoch, the Prince of Evil Earth.</text>		<text>	You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. When you hit with it, the target takes an extra 1d8 thunder damage.</text>		<text>	Earth Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Ironfang:</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can speak Terran fluently.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You have resistance to acid damage.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You have tremorsense out to a range of 60 feet.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can sense the presence of precious metals and stones within 60 feet of you, but not their exact location.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on an earth elemental. Once you have done so, Ironfang can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Shatter: Ironfang has 3 charges. You can use your action to expend 1 charge and cast the 2nd-level version of shatter (DC 17). Ironfang regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn. </text>		<text>	The Rumbling: While inside an earth node, you can perform a ritual called the Rumbling, using Ironfang to create a devastation orb of earth (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Ironfang can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Flaw: Ironfang heightens its wielder's destructive nature. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I like to break things and cause ruin."</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, war pick</text>		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 224</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property></property>		<range></range>		<roll>1d8</roll>		<roll>1d3</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Javelin of Backbiting</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare, cursed (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>2</weight>		<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you throw it, its normal and long ranges both increase by 30 feet (included in range). and it deals one extra die of damage on a hit. After you throw it and it hits or misses, it flies back to your hand immediately. </text>		<text>Curse: This weapon is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. Until the curse is broken with remove curse or similar magic, you are unwilling to part with the weapon, keeping it within reach at all times. In addition, you have disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one. </text>		<text>	Whenever you roll a 1 on an attack roll using this weapon, the weapon bends or flies to hit you in the back. Make a new attack roll with advantage against your own AC. If the result is a hit, you take damage as if you had attacked yourself with the spear.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, javelin</text>		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>T</property>		<range>60/150</range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Korolnor Scepter</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>2</weight>		<text>The Korolnor Scepter is one of ten Ruling Scepters of Shanatar, forged by the dwarven gods and given to the ruling houses of the ancient dwarven empire. The Korolnor Scepter's location was unknown for the longest time until a storm giant queen, Neri, found it in a barnacle- covered shipwreck at the bottom of the Trackless Sea. The Ruling Scepters are all roughly the same size and shape, but their materials and properties vary. The Korolnor Scepter is a tapered mithral rod as thick and long as a dwarf's forearm, with a small platinum knob at the bottom and a rounded disk adorned with a ring of seven tiny blue gems at the top. </text>		<text>	You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this scepter, which can be wielded as a magic club. </text>		<text>	You can use the properties of the Wyrmskull Throne, as well as the properties of the scepter itself. The scepter has 10 charges, and it regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges at dawn. Its properties are as follows: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; If you are underground or underwater, you can use an action to expend 1 charge to determine the distance to the surface. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; As an action, you can expend 2 charges to cast the sending spell from the scepter. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; As an action, you can expend 3 charges to cast the teleport spell from the scepter. If the destination is within 60 feet of the Wyrmskull Throne, there is no chance of a teleport error or mishap occurring.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, club</text>		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 236</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +3</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +3</modifier>		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>B</dmgType>		<property>L</property>		<range></range>		<roll>1d6+4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Lightbringer</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>unique</detail>		<weight>4</weight>		<text>This +1 mace was made for a cleric of Lathander, the god of dawn. The head of the mace is shaped like a sunburst and made of solid brass. Named Lightbringer, this weapon glows as bright as a torch when its wielder commands. While glowing, the mace deals an extar 1d6 radiant damage to undead creatures.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, mace</text>		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver, p. 48</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>B</dmgType>		<property></property>		<range></range>		<roll>1d6</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Orcsplitter</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement by a good-aligned dwarf, fighter, or paladin)</detail>		<weight>7</weight>		<text>A mighty axe wielded long ago by the dwarf king Torhild Flametongue, Orcsplitter is a battered weapon that appears unremarkable at first glance. Its head is graven with the Dwarvish runes for "orc," but the runes are depicted with a gap or slash through the markings; the word "orc" is literally split in two.</text>		<text>	You gain the following benefits while holding this magic weapon:</text>		<text>	&#8226; You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it.</text>		<text>	&#8226; When you roll a 20 on an attack roll with this weapon against an orc, that orc must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or drop to 0 hit points.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can't be surprised by orcs while you're not incapacitated. You are also aware when orcs are within 120 feet of you and aren't behind total cover, although you don't know their location.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You and any of your friends within 30 feet of you can't be frightened while you're not incapacitated. </text>		<text>	Sentience: Orcsplitter is a sentient, lawful good weapon with an Intelligence of 6, a Wisdom of 15, and a Charisma of 10. It can see and hear out to 120 feet and has darkvision. It communicates by transmitting emotions to its wielder, although on rare occasions it uses a limited form of telepathy to bring to the wielder's mind a couplet or stanza of ancient Dwarvish verse. </text>		<text>	Personality: Orcsplitter is grim, taciturn, and inflexible. It knows little more than the desire to face orcs in battle and serve a courageous, just wielder. It disdains cowards and any form of duplicity, deception, or disloyalty. The weapon's purpose is to defend dwarves and to serve as a symbol of dwarven resolve. It hates the traditional foes of dwarves &#8212; giants, goblins, and, most of all, orcs &#8212; and silently urges its possessor to meet such creatures in battle.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.  When not attacking, you may hold the weapon in one hand.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, greataxe</text>		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 224</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d12</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>H,2H</property>		<range></range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Saint Markovia's Thighbone</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>4</weight>		<text>Saint Markovia's thighbone has the properties of a mace of disruption. If it scores one or more hits against a vampire or a vampire spawn in the course of a single battle, the thighbone crumbles into dust once the battle concludes.</text>		<text>	As a youth, Markovia followed her heart and became a priest of the Morninglord soon after her eighteenth birthday. She proved to be a charismatic proselytizer and, before the age of thirty, had gained a reputation for allowing no evil to stand before her.</text>		<text>	Markovia had long considered Strahd a mad tyrant, but only after his transformation into a vampire did she dare to challenge him. As she rallied her followers and prepared to march on Castle Ravenloft, Strahd sent a group of vampire spawn to her abbey. They confronted Markovia and were destroyed to a one.</text>		<text>	Suffused with confidence born of a righteous victory, Markovia advanced on Castle Ravenloft. A great battle raged from the catacombs to the parapets. In the end, Markovia never returned to Barovia, and Strahd long afterward walked with a limp and a grimace of pain. It is said that he trapped Markovia in a crypt beneath his castle, and her remains linger there yet.</text>		<text>	The essence of Markovia's saintliness passed partly into her bones as the rest of her body decomposed. Her remaining thighbone is imbued with power that inflicts grievous injury on the undead.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Mace of Disruption: When you hit a fiend or an undead with this magic weapon, that creature takes an extra 2d6 radiant damage. If the target has 25 hit points or fewer after taking this damage, it must succeed on a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or be destroyed. On a successful save, the creature becomes frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>		<text>	While you hold this weapon, it sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, mace</text>		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 222</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>B</dmgType>		<property></property>		<range></range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Shatterspike</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>You have a +l bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic longsword. If it hits an object, the hit is automatically a critical hit, and it can deal bludgeoning or slashing damage to the object (your choice). Further, damage from nonmagical sources can't harm the weapon.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, longsword</text>		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>V</property>		<range></range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spear of Backbiting</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare, cursed (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you throw it, its normal and long ranges both increase by 30 feet (included in range). and it deals one extra die of damage on a hit. After you throw it and it hits or misses, it flies back to your hand immediately. </text>		<text>Curse: This weapon is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. Until the curse is broken with remove curse or similar magic, you are unwilling to part with the weapon, keeping it within reach at all times. In addition, you have disadvantage on attack rolls made with weapons other than this one. </text>		<text>	Whenever you roll a 1 on an attack roll using this weapon, the weapon bends or flies to hit you in the back. Make a new attack roll with advantage against your own AC. If the result is a hit, you take damage as if you had attacked yourself with the spear.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, spear</text>		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>T,V</property>		<range>50/90</range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Sunsword</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>The Sunsword is a unique blade once possessed by Strahd's brother, Sergei von Zarovich. In its original form, it had a platinum hilt and guard, and a thin crystal blade as strong as steel.</text>		<text>	Strahd employed a powerful wizard named Khazan to destroy the weapon after Sergei's death. The first part of the process required the hilt and the blade to be separated, which Khazan accomplished. While Khazan was busying himself destroying the blade, his apprentice stole the hilt and fled. Khazan later located his apprentice's mutilated corpse in the Svalich Woods, but the hilt was nowhere to be found. To avoid the vampire's wrath, Khazan told Strahd that the entire weapon had been destroyed.</text>		<text>	The hilt, which is sentient, knows that it can never be reunited with its original crystal blade. It has, however, gained the properties of a sun blade.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Sentience: The Sunsword is a sentient chaotic good weapon with an Intelligence of 11, a Wisdom of 17, and a Charisma of 16. It has hearing and normal vision out to a range of 60 feet. The weapon communicates by transmitting emotions to the creature carrying it or wielding it.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Personality: The Sunsword's special purpose is to destroy Strahd, not so much because it wants to free the land of Barovia from evil but because it wants revenge for the loss of its crystal blade. The weapon secretly fears its own destruction.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Sun blade: This item appears to be a longsword hilt. While grasping the hilt, you can use a bonus action to cause a blade of pure radiance to spring into existence, or make the blade disappear. While the blade exists, this magic longsword has the finesse property. If you are proficient with shortswords or longswords, you are proficient with the sun blade.</text>		<text>	You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, which deals radiant damage instead of slashing damage. When you hit an undead with it, that target takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage.</text>		<text>	The sword's luminous blade emits bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet. The light is sunlight. While the blade persists, you can use an action to expand or reduce its radius of bright and dim light by 5 feet each, to a maximum of 30 feet each or a minimum of 10 feet each.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, longsword, shortsword</text>		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 223</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>F,V</property>		<range></range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Talon</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>unique</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>Talon is a +1 longsword in a silver-chased scabbard. Its hilt is worked in the shape of a bird of prey with outspread wings. It once belonged to a great knight named Aldith Tresendar, known as the Black Hawk.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, longsword</text>		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver, p. 24</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>V</property>		<range></range>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Tinderstrike</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>A flint dagger, Tinderstrike is uncommonly sharp, and sparks cascade off its edge whenever it strikes something solid. Its handle is always warm to the touch, and the blade smolders for 1d4 minutes after it is used to deal damage. It contains a spark of Imix, Prince of Evil Fire.</text>		<text>	You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. When you hit with it, the target takes an extra 2d6 fire damage.</text>		<text>	Fire Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Tinderstrike:</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can speak Ignan fluently.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You have resistance to fire damage.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on a fire elemental. Once you have done so, Tinderstrike can't be used this way again until the next dawn. </text>		<text>	Dance of the All-Consuming Fire: While inside a fire node, you can perform a ritual called the Dance of the All-Consuming Fire, using Tinderstrike to create a devastation orb of fire (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Tinderstrike can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn. </text>		<text>	Flaw: Tinderstrike makes its wielder impatient and rash. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I act without thinking and take risks without weighing the consequences."</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, dagger</text>		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 224</text>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>F,L,T</property>		<range>20/60</range>		<roll>2d6</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Waythe</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>6</weight>		<text>Waythe is a unique greatsword most recently in the possession of a high-ranking cloud giant ambassador. </text>		<text>	You gain a +l bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When you hit a creature of the giant type with it, the giant takes an extra 2d6 slashing damage, and it must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or fall prone. </text>		<text>	The sword also functions as a wand of enemy detection. It regains all of its expended charges at dawn and isn't at risk of crumbling if its last charge is used. </text>		<text>	Sentience: Waythe is a sentient weapon of neutral good alignment, with an Intelligence of 12, a Wisdom of 2, and a Charisma of 14. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet. </text>		<text>	The weapon can speak and understand Giant and Common, and it can communicate telepathically with its wielder. </text>		<text>	Personality: This sword believes in freedom and allowing others to live as they see fit. It is protective of its friends, and wants to be friends with a like-minded wielder. (It takes only 1 minute for a good-aligned character to gain attunement with the sword.) Waythe is courageous to the point of foolhardiness, however, and vocally urges bold action. It is likely to come into conflict with an evil or a timid wielder.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Prone:</text>		<text>&#8226; A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>&#8226; The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>&#8226; An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.  When not attacking, you may hold the weapon in one hand.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: martial, greatsword</text>		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>S</dmgType>		<property>H,2H</property>		<range></range>		<roll>2d6</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Windvane</name>		<type>M</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>A silver spear, Windvane has dark sapphires on the filigreed surface of its polished head. Held by its shining haft, the weapon feels insubstantial, as if clutching a cool, gently flowing breeze. The spear contains a spark of Yan-C-Bin, the Prince of Evil Air.</text>		<text>	You have a +2 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon, which has the finesse weapon property. When you hit with it, the target takes an extra 1d6 lightning damage.</text>		<text>	Air Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Windvane:</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can speak Auran fluently.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You have resistance to lightning damage.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on an air elemental. Once you have done so, Windvane can't be used this way again until the next dawn. </text>		<text>	Song of the Four Winds: While inside an air node, you can perform a ritual called the Song of the Four Winds, using Windvane to create a devastation orb of air (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Windvane can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn. </text>		<text>	Flaw: Windvane makes its wielder mercurial and unreliable. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I break my vows and plans. Duty and honor mean nothing to me."</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, spear</text>		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 224</text>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>T,V</property>		<range>20/60</range>		<roll>1d6</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Dragonguard</name>		<type>MA</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>unique</detail>		<weight>20</weight>		<text>This +1 breastplate has a gold dragon motif worked into its design. Created for a human hero of Neverwinter named Tergon, it grants its wearer advantage on saving throws against the breath weapons of creatures that have the dragon type.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver, p. 48</text>		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>		<ac>15</ac>		<strength></strength>		<stealth></stealth>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Bottled Breath</name>		<type>P</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon</detail>		<weight>0.5</weight>		<text>This bottle contains a breath of elemental air. When you inhale it, you either exhale it or hold it.</text>		<text>	If you inhale the breath, you gain the effect of the gust of wind spell. If you hold the breath, you don't need to breathe for 1 hour, though you can end this benefit early (for example, to speak). Ending it early doesn't give you the benefit of exhaling the breath.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Potion of Beast Mind Control</name>		<type>P</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare</detail>		<weight>0.5</weight>		<text>When you drink a potion of mind control, you can cast a dominate beast spell (save DC 15) on a specific creature if you do so before the end of your next turn. If you don't, the potion is wasted. </text>		<text>	If the target's initial saving throw fails, the effect lasts for 1 hour, with no concentration required on your part. The charmed creature has disadvantage on new saving throws to break the effect during this time.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Potion of Giant Size</name>		<type>P</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>When you drink this potion, you become Huge for 24 hours if you are Medium or smaller, otherwise the potion does nothing. For that duration, your Strength becomes 25, if it isn't already higher, and your hit point maximum is doubled (your current hit points are doubled when you drink the potion). In addition, the reach of your melee attacks increases by 5 feet. </text>		<text>	Everything you are carrying and wearing also increases in size for the duration. When rolling damage for weapons enlarged in this manner, roll three times the normal number of dice; for example, an enlarged longsword would deal 3d8 slashing damage (instead of 1d8), or 3d10 slashing damage (instead of 1dlO) when used with two hands. </text>		<text>	When the effect ends, any hit points you have above your hit point maximum become temporary hit points. </text>		<text>	This potion is a pale white liquid made from the tongue of a giant clam, with a pungent aroma akin to that of rotting algae. It tastes sweet, however, when consumed.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 238</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Potion of Human Mind Control</name>		<type>P</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare</detail>		<weight>0.5</weight>		<text>When you drink a potion of mind control, you can cast a dominate person spell (save DC 15) on a specific creature if you do so before the end of your next turn. If you don't, the potion is wasted. </text>		<text>	If the target's initial saving throw fails, the effect lasts for 1 hour, with no concentration required on your part. The charmed creature has disadvantage on new saving throws to break the effect during this time.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Potion of Monster Mind Control</name>		<type>P</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare</detail>		<weight>0.5</weight>		<text>When you drink a potion of mind control, you can cast a dominate monster spell (save DC 15) on a specific creature if you do so before the end of your next turn. If you don't, the potion is wasted. </text>		<text>	If the target's initial saving throw fails, the effect lasts for 1 hour, with no concentration required on your part. The charmed creature has disadvantage on new saving throws to break the effect during this time.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Seeker Dart</name>		<type>R</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon</detail>		<weight>0.25</weight>		<text>This small dart is decorated with designs like windy spirals that span the length of its shaft.</text>		<text>	When you whisper the word "seek" and hurl this dart, it seeks out a target of your choice within 120 feet of you. You must have seen the target before, but you don't need to see it now. If the target isn't within range or if there is no clear path to it, the dart falls to the ground, its magic spent and wasted. Otherwise, elemental winds guide the dart instantly through the air to the target. The dart can pass though openings as narrow as 1 inch wide and can change direction to fly around corners.</text>		<text>	When the dart reaches its target, the target must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d4 piercing damage and 3d4 lightning damage. The dart's magic is then spent, and it becomes an ordinary dart.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, dart</text>		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 223</text>		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>P</dmgType>		<property>F,T</property>		<range>20/60</range>		<roll>3d4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Storm Boomerang</name>		<type>R</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This boomerang is a ranged weapon carved from griffon bone and etched with the symbol of elemental air. When thrown, it has a range of 60/120 feet, and any creature that is proficient with the javelin is also proficient with this weapon. On a hit, the boomerang deals 1d4 bludgeoning damage and 3d4 thunder damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of its next turn. On a miss, the boomerang returns to the thrower's hand.</text>		<text>	Once the boomerang deals thunder damage to a target, the weapon loses its ability to deal thunder damage and its ability to stun a target. These properties return after the boomerang spends at least 1 hour inside an elemental air node.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Stunned:</text>		<text>&#8226; A stunned creature is incapacitated, meaning it can't take actions or reactions, can't move, and can speak only falteringly.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>&#8226; The creature automatically fails Strength and Dexterity saving throws.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>&#8226; Attack rolls against the creature have advantage.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, javelin</text>		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 223</text>		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>		<dmg2></dmg2>		<dmgType>B</dmgType>		<property></property>		<range>60/120</range>		<roll>3d4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Gulthias Staff</name>		<type>ST</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>4</weight>		<text>Made from the branch of a Gulthias tree (see the blights entry of the Monster Manual), a Gulthias staff is a spongy, black length of wood. Its evil makes beasts visibly uncomfortable while within 30 feet of it. The staff has 10 charges and regains 1d6+4 of its expended charges daily at dusk.</text>		<text>	If the staff is broken or burned to ashes, its wood releases a terrible, inhuman scream that can be heard out to a range of 300 feet. All blights that can hear the scream immediately wither and die.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Vampiric Strike: The staff can be wielded as a magic quarterstaff. On a hit, it deals damage as a normal quarterstaff, and you can expend 1 charge to regain a number of hit points equal to the damage dealt by the weapon. Each time a charge is spent, red blood oozes from the staff's pores, and you must succeed on a DC 12 Wisdom saving throw or be afflicted with short term madness (see "Madness" in chapter 8 of the Dungeon Master's Guide).</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Blight Bane: While you are attuned to the staff, blights and other evil plant creatures don't regard you as hostile unless you harm them.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property &#8212; the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, quarterstaff</text>		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 221</text>		<roll>1d6+4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spider Staff</name>		<type>ST</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>requires attunement</detail>		<weight>6</weight>		<text>The top of this black, adamantine staff is shaped like a spider. The staff weighs 6 pounds. You must be attuned to the staff to gain its benefits and cast its spells. The staff can be wielded as a quarterstaff. It deals 1d6 extra poison damage on a hit when used to make a weapon attack.</text>		<text>	 The staff has 10 charges, which are used to fuel the spells within it. With the staff in hand, you can use your action to cast one of the following spells from the staff if the spell is on your class's spell list: spider climb (1 charge) or web (2 charges, spell save DC 15). No components are required.</text>		<text>	 The staff regains 1d6+4 expended charges each day at dusk. If you expend the staff's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff crumbles to dust and is destroyed.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, quarterstaff</text>		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver p. 53</text>		<roll>1d6+4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Staff of Defense</name>		<type>ST</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>requires attunement</detail>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>This slender, hollow staff is made of glass yet is as strong as oak. It weighs 3 pounds. You must be attuned to the staff to gain its benefits and cast its spells.</text>		<text>	 While holding the staff, you have a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</text>		<text>	 The staff has 10 charges, which are used to fuel the spells within it. With the staff in hand, you can use your action to cast one of the following spells from the staff if the spell is on your class's spell list: mage armor (1 charge) or shield (2 charges). No components are required.</text>		<text>	 The staff regains 1d6+4 expended charges each day at dawn. If you expend the staff's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff shatters and is destroyed.</text>		<text />		<text>Proficiency: simple, quarterstaff</text>		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver p. 53</text>		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>		<roll>1d6+4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Amulet of Protection from Turning</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>While you wear this amulet of silver and turquoise, you have advantage on saving throws against effects that turn undead. </text>		<text>	If you fail a saving throw against such an effect, you can choose to succeed instead. You can do so three times, and expended uses recharge daily at dawn. </text>		<text>	Each time an effect that turns undead is used against you, the amulet glows with silvery blue light for a few seconds.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Balance of Harmony</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This scale bears celestial symbols on one pan and fiendish symbols on the other. You can use the scale to cast detect evil and good as a ritual. Doing so requires you to place the scale on a solid surface, then sprinkle the pans with holy water or place a transparent gem worth 100 gp in each pan. The scale remains motionless if it detects nothing, tips to one side or the other for good (consecrated) or evil (desecrated), and fluctuates slightly if it detects a creature appropriate to the spell but neither good nor evil. By touching the scales after casting the ritual, you instantly learn any information the spell can normally convey, and then the effect ends.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Balloon Pack</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This backpack contains the spirit of an air elemental and a compact leather balloon. While you're wearing the backpack, you can deploy the balloon as an action and gain the effect of the levitate spell for 10 minutes, targeting yourself and requiring no concentration. Alternatively, you can use a reaction to deploy the balloon when you're falling and gain the effect of the feather fall spell for yourself.</text>		<text>	When either spell ends, the balloon slowly deflates as the elemental spirit escapes and returns to the Elemental Plane of Air. As the balloon deflates, you descend gently toward the ground for up to 60 feet. IF you are still in the air at the end of this distance, you fall if you have no other means of staying aloft.</text>		<text>	After the spirit departs, the backpack's property is unusable unless the backpack is recharged for 1 hour in an elemental air node, which binds another spirit to the backpack.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Banner of the Krig Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>Crafted from a thick, red fabric, this banner measures 5 feet high and 3 feet wide. The krig (war) rune is displayed on the fabric with round, metal plates sewn into it. It can be attached to a 10-foot pole to serve as a standard. Furling or unfurling the banner requires an action. The banner has the following properties. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Mark of Courage: As a bonus action, you can touch the unfurled banner and cause it to emanate courage. You and your allies are immune to the frightened condition while within 20 feet of it. This benefit lasts for 10 minutes or until the banner is furled. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Sentinel Standard: You can see invisible creatures while they are within 20 feet of the unfurled banner and within your line of sight. Standard's Shield. As a bonus action, you can touch the unfurled banner and invoke this power. Any ranged attack roll that targets you or an ally of yours has disadvantage if the target is within 20 feet of the unfurled banner. This benefit lasts for 1 minute or until the banner is furled. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Gift of Battle: You can transfer the banner's magic to a place by tracing the krig rune on the ground with your finger. The point where you trace it becomes the center of a spherical area of magic that has a 500-foot radius and that is fixed to the place. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the banner to be within 5 feet of you and during which you choose creatures, creature types, or both that will benefit from the magic. At the end, the banner is destroyed, and the area gains the following property: </text>		<text>While in the 500-foot-radius sphere, the creatures you chose during the transfer process are immune to the frightened condition and gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and AC.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 235</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Black Dragon Mask</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This horned mask of glossy ebony has horns and a skull-like mien. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Damage Absorption: You have damage resistance to acid. If you already have damage resistance to acid from another source, you gain immunity to acid damage. If you already have immunity to acid damage from another source, you regain hit points equal to half of any acid damage you are dealt.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision with a radius of 60 feet, or an additional 60 feet of darkvision if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to a range of 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against black dragons.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Water Breathing: You can breathe underwater.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen p. 94</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Blod Stone</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This diamond contains the blood of a creature-blood that appears in the form of the blod (blood) rune. While the item is on your person, you can use your action to divine the location of the creature nearest to you that is related to the blood in the item and that isn't undead. You sense the distance and direction of the creature relative to your location. The creature is either the one whose blood is in the item or a blood relative. </text>		<text>	This item is made from a large diamond worth at least 5,000 gp. When the blood of a creature is poured onto it during the creation process, the blood seeps into the heart of the gem. If the gem is destroyed, the blood evaporates and is gone forever. A vengeful being might use a blod stone to hunt down an entire bloodline. Such stones are sometimes given as gifts to siblings or handed down from parent to child.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 235</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Blue Dragon Mask</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This mask of glossy azure has spikes around its edges and a ridged horn in its center. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Damage Absorption: You have resistance against lightning damage. If you already have resistance to lightning damage from another source, you instead have immunity to lightning damage. If you already have immunity to lightning damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to acid damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Blue Dragons.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Lingering Shock: If you deal lightning damage to a creature, it can't take reactions until its next turn.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement p. 4</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Bracelet of Rock Magic</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare, cursed (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>While you wear this gold bracelet, it grants you immunity to being petrified, and it allows you to cast flesh to stone (save DC 15) as an action. Once the spell has been cast three times, the bracelet can no longer cast it. Thereafter, you can cast stone shape as an action. After you have done this thirteen times, the bracelet loses its magic and turns from gold to lead. </text>		<text>Curse: The bracelet's affinity with earth manifests as an unusual curse. Creatures of flesh that are strongly related to earth and stone, such as stone giants and dwarves, have advantage on the saving throw against flesh to stone cast from the bracelet. If such a creature's save is successful, the bracelet breaks your attunement to it and casts the spell on you. You make your saving throw with disadvantage, and on a failed save you are petrified instantly.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Claw of the Wyrm Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This dragon's claw has been covered with a coat of molten silver, upon which has been inscribed the wyrm (dragon) rune. The claw has the following properties. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Wyrmslayer: As an action, you can point the claw at a dragon within 30 feet of you. The dragon must then succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or gain vulnerability to all damage types until the end of your next turn. This property can be used three times. The claw regains all expended uses at the next dawn. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Wyrm Shield: While the claw is displayed on your person, you have resistance to the damage caused by any dragon's breath weapon. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Wyrm Ward: You can transfer the claw's magic to a place by tracing the wyrm rune on the ground with your finger. The point where you trace it becomes the center of a spherical area of magic that has a 100-foot radius and that is fixed to the place. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the claw to be within 5 feet of you. At the end, the claw is destroyed, and the area gains the following property: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>While in the 100-foot-radius sphere, any dragon has disadvantage on saving throws and can have a flying speed no higher than 10 feet.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 235</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Claws of the Umber Hulk</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>These heavy gauntlets of brown iron are forged in the shape an umber hulk's claws, and they fit the wearer's hands and forearms all the way up to the elbow. While wearing both claws, you gain a burrowing speed of 20 feet, and you can tunnel through solid rock at a rate of 1 foot per round.</text>		<text>	You can use a claw as a melee weapon while wearing it. You have proficiency with it, and it deals 1d8 slashing damage on a hit (your Strength modifier applies to the attack and damage rolls, as normal)</text>		<text>	While wearing the claws, you can't manipulate objects or cast spells with somatic components</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Conch of Teleportation</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This item is an ordinary, albeit rather large, conch shell that has been inscribed with the uvar rune. The conch measures 2 1/2 feet long and weighs 20 pounds. </text>		<text>	As an action, you can cast the teleport spell by blowing into the shell. The destination is fixed, and there is no chance of either a mishap or the spell being off target. Anyone teleported by the conch appears in a specific location designated by the item's creator at the time the uvar rune is inscribed on the conch. It doesn't allow teleportation to any other destination. Once its spell is cast, the conch can't be used again until the next dawn.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 236</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Devastation Orb of Air</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>		<text>	A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>		<text>	A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>		<text>	Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>		<text>	Air Orb: When this orb detonates, it creates a powerful windstorm that lasts for 1 hour. Whenever a creature ends its turn exposed to the wind, the creature must succeed on a DC 18 Constitution saving throw or take 1d4 bludgeoning damage, as the wind and debris batter it. The wind is strong enough to uproot weak trees and destroy light structures after at least 10 minutes of exposure. Otherwise, the rules for strong wind apply, as detailed in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 222</text>		<roll>1d4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Devastation Orb of Earth</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>		<text>	A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>		<text>	A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>		<text>	Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>		<text>	Earth Orb: When this orb detonates, it subjects the area to the effects of the earthquake spell for 1 minute (spell save DC 18). For the purpose of the spell's effects, the spell is cast on the turn that the orb explodes.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Devastation Orb of Fire</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>		<text>	A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>		<text>	A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>		<text>	Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>		<text>	Fire Orb: When this orb detonates, it creates a dry heat wave that lasts for 24 hours. Within the area of effect, the rules for extreme heat apply, as detailed in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide. At the end of each hour, there is a ten percent chance that the heat wave starts a wildfire in a random location within the area of effect. The wildfire covers a 10-foot-square area initially but expands to fill another 10-foot square each round until the fire is extinguished or burns itself out. A creature that comes within 10 feet of a wildfire for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there takes 3d6 fire damage.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 222</text>		<roll></roll>		<roll>3d6</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Devastation Orb of Water</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>		<text>	A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>		<text>	A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>		<text>	Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>		<text>	Water Orb: When this orb detonates, it creates a torrential rainstorm that lasts for 24 hours. Within the area of effect, the rules for heavy precipitation apply, as detailed in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide. If there is a substantial body of water in the area, it floods after 2d10 hours of heavy rain, rising 10 feet above its banks and inundating the surrounding area. The flood advances at a rate of 100 feet per round, moving away from the body of water where it began until it reaches the edge of the area of effect: at that point, the water flows downhill (and possibly recedes back to its origin). Light structures collapse and wash away. Any Large or smaller creature caught in the flood's path is swept away. The flooding destroys crops and might trigger mudslides, depending on the terrain.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Draakhorn</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>unique</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>The Draakhorn was a gift from Tiamat in the war between dragons and giants. It was once the horn of her ancient red dragon consort, Ephelomon, that she gave to dragonkind to help them in their war against the giants. The Draakhorn is a signaling device, and it is so large that it requires two Medium creatures (or one Large or larger) to hold it while a third creature sounds it, making the earth resonate to its call. The horn has been blasted with fire into a dark ebony hue and is wrapped in bands of bronze with draconic runes that glow with purple eldritch fire.</text>		<text>	The low, moaning drone of the Draakhorn discomfits normal animals within a few miles, and it alerts all dragons within two thousand miles to rise and be wary, for great danger is at hand. Coded blasts were once used to signal specific messages. Knowledge of those codes has been lost to the ages.</text>		<text>	Those with knowledge of the Draakhorn's history know that it was first built to signal danger to chromatic dragons &#8212; a purpose the Cult of the Dragon has corrupted to call chromatic dragons to the Well of Dragons from across the North.</text>		<text>	Within 50 feet of any enclosed space where the horn is blown, the air begins to shimmer from the sound. Any character within 20 feet of the entry to the enclosed space must succeed on a DC 12 Strength check to continue pushing against the pressure of the sound. A failure indicates the character can advance no farther toward the entry.</text>		<text>	For any character entering the enclosed space, the sound fades to silence &#8212; because any creature that enters the enclosed space is temporarily deafened and must make a DC 12 Constitution saving throw. Success indicates the deafness ends 2 minutes after the Draakhorn ceases to sound. Failure indicates the character remains deafened for 1 hour after the Draakhorn ceases to sound.</text>		<text>	While the horn is sounding, a creature must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw the first time on a turn the creature enters a 150-foot cone in front of the horn or starts its turn there. On a failed save, the creature takes 27 (6d8) thunder damage and is knocked prone. On a successful save, the creature takes half damage and isn't knocked prone. </text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Deafened:</text>		<text>&#8226; A deafened creature can't hear and automatically fails any ability check that requires hearing. </text>		<text>	</text>		<text>Prone:</text>		<text>&#8226; A prone creature's only movement option is to crawl, unless it stands up and thereby ends the condition.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>&#8226; The creature has disadvantage on attack rolls.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>&#8226; An attack roll against the creature has advantage if the attacker is within 5 feet of the creature. Otherwise, the attack roll has disadvantage.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: The Rise of Tiamat p. 93</text>		<roll>6d8</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Eagle Whistle</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>While you blow an eagle whistle continuously, you can fly twice as fast as your walking speed. You can blow the whistle continuously for a number of rounds equal to 5 + five times your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 round) or until you talk, hold your breath, or start suffocating. A use of the whistle also ends if you land. If you are aloft when you stop blowing the whistle, you fall. </text>		<text>	The whistle has three uses. It regains expended uses daily at dawn.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Gavel of the Venn Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This wooden gavel is small by giant reckoning but nearly the size of a warhammer in human hands. The venn (friend) rune is inscribed in mithral in the base of the haft. Among giants, this item is used as part of rituals to resolve disputes. The gavel has the following properties. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Arbiter's Shield: At the start of every combat, attack rolls against you have disadvantage before the start of your first turn, provided that the gavel is on your person. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Bond of Amity: As an action, you can use the gavel to strike a point on a hard surface. The first time in the next minute that a creature within 60 feet of that point deals damage to another creature with an attack that hits, the attacker takes psychic damage equal to half the damage it dealt to the target. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Gift of Truth: You can transfer the gavel's magic to a place by tracing the venn rune on the ground with your finger. The point where you trace it becomes the center of a spherical area of magic that has a 30-foot radius and that is fixed to the place. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the gavel to be within 5 feet of you. At the end, the gavel is destroyed, and the area gains the following property: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Whenever a creature utters a lie while within the 30-foot-radius sphere, that creature takes 5 psychic damage and flinches visibly.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 236</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Green Dragon Mask</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This mottled green mask is surmounted by a frilled crest and has leathery spiked plates along its jaw. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Damage Absorption: You have resistance against poison damage. If you already have resistance to poison damage from another source, you instead have immunity to poison damage. If you already have immunity to poison damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to poison damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Green Dragons.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Water Breathing: You can breathe underwater.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement p. 4</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Hell Hound Cloak</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare, cursed (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This dark cloak is made of cured hell hound hide. As an action, you can command the cloak to transform you into a hell hound for up to 1 hour. The transformation otherwise functions as the polymorph spell, but you can use a bonus action to revert to your normal form. </text>		<text>Curse: This cloak is cursed with the essence of a hell hound, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. Until the curse is broken with remove curse or similar magic, you are unwilling to part with the cloak, keeping it within reach at all times. </text>		<text>	The sixth time you use the cloak, and each time thereafter, you must make a DC 15 Charisma saving throw. On a failed save, the transformation lasts until dispelled or until you drop to O hit points, and you can't willingly return to normal form. If you ever remain in hell hound form for 6 hours, the transformation becomes permanent and you lose your sense of self. All your statistics are then replaced by those of a hell hound. Thereafter, only remove curse or similar magic allows you to regain your identity and return to normal. If you remain in this permanent form for 6 days, only a wish spell can reverse the transformation.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Holy Symbol of Ravenkind</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement by a cleric or paladin of good alignment)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>The Holy Symbol of Ravenkind is a unique holy symbol sacred to the good-hearted faithful of Barovia. It predates the establishment of any church in Barovia. According to legend, it was delivered to a paladin named Lugdana by a giant raven &#8212; or an angel in the form of a giant raven. Lugdana used the holy symbol to root out and destroy nests of vampires until her death. The high priests of Ravenloft kept and wore the holy symbol after Lugdana's passing.</text>		<text>	The holy symbol is a platinum amulet shaped like the sun, with a large crystal embedded in its center.</text>		<text>	The holy symbol has 10 charges for the following properties. It regains 1d6+4 charges daily at dawn.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Hold Vampires: As an Action, you can expend 1 charge and present the holy symbol to make it flare with holy power. Vampires and vampire spawn within 30 feet of the holy symbol when it flares must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, a target is paralyzed for 1 minute. It can repeat the saving throw at the end of its turns to end the effect on itself.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Turn Undead: If you have the Turn Undead or the Turn the Unholy feature, you can expend 3 charges when you present the holy symbol while using that feature. When you do so, undead have disadvantage on their saving throws against the effect.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Sunlight: As an action, you can expend 5 charges while presenting the holy symbol to make it shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. The light is sunlight and lasts for 10 minutes or until you end the effect (no action required).</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 222</text>		<roll>1d6+4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Icon of Ravenloft</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement by a creature of good alignment)</detail>		<weight>10</weight>		<text>The Icon of Ravenloft is a 12-inch tall statuette made of the purest silver, weighing 10 pounds. It depicts a cleric kneeling in supplication.</text>		<text>	The icon was given to Strahd by the archpriest Ciril Romulich, an old family friend, to consecrate the castle and its chapel.</text>		<text>	While within 30 feet of the icon, a creature is under the effect of a protection from evil and good spell against fiends and undead. Only a creature attuned to the icon can use its other properties.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Augury: You can use an action to cast an augury spell from the icon, with no material components required. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Bane of the Undead: You can use the icon as a holy symbol while using the Turn Undead or Turn the Unholy feature. If you do so, increase the save DC by 2.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Cure Wounds: While holding the icon, you can take an action to heal one creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. The target regains 3d8+3 hit points, unless it is an undead, a construct, or a fiend. Once used, this property can't be used again until the next dawn.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Curse of Strahd, p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Ingot of the Skold Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This appears to be a simple ingot of iron ore, about a foot long and a few inches across. Inspection of its surface reveals the faint, silvery outline of the skold (shield) rune. The ingot has the following properties, which work only while it's on your person. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Runic Shield: You have a + 1 bonus to AC. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Shield Bond: As a bonus action, choose a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you, other than yourself. Until the end of your next turn, any damage the target takes is reduced to l, but you take half the damage prevented in this way. The damage you take can't be reduced in any way. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Shield Ward: You can transfer the ingot's magic to a nonmagical item &#8212; a shield or a two-handed melee weapon &#8212; by tracing the skold rune there with your finger. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the two items to be within 5 feet of each other. At the end, the ingot is destroyed, and the rune appears in silver on the chosen item, which gains a benefit based on its form: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Shield: The shield is now a rare magic item that requires attunement. Its magic gives you a + 1 bonus to AC, and the first time after each of your long rests that damage reduces you to O hit points, you are instead reduced to 1 hit point. You must be wielding the shield to gain these benefits. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Weapon: The weapon is now an uncommon magic weapon. It grants you a +l bonus to AC while you're holding it.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 236</text>		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Insignia of Claws</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>The jewels in the insignia of the Cult of the Dragon flare with purple light when you enter combat, empowering your natural fists or natural weapons.</text>		<text>	While wearing the insignia you gain a +1 bonus to the attack rolls and the damage rolls you make with unarmed strikes and natural weapons. Such attacks are considered to be magical.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen p. 94</text>		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Loadstone</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare, cursed</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This stone is a large gem worth 150 gp. </text>		<text>Curse: The stone is cursed, but its magical nature is hidden; detect magic doesn't detect it. An identify spell reveals the stone's true nature. If you use the Dash or Disengage action while the stone is on your person, its curse activates. Until the curse is broken with remove curse or similar magic, your speed is reduced by 5 feet, and your maximum load and maximum lift capacities are halved. You also become unwilling to part with the stone.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>		<modifier category="bonus">speed -5</modifier>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Lost Crown of Besilmer</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This dwarven battle-helm consists of a sturdy open-faced steel helmet, decorated with a golden circlet above the brow from which seven small gold spikes project upward. You gain the following benefits while wearing the crown:</text>		<text>	&#8226; You have resistance to psychic damage.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You have advantage on saving throws against effects that would charm you.</text>		<text>	&#8226; You can use a bonus action to inspire one creature you can see that is within 60 feet of you and that can see or hear you. Once before the end of your next turn, the inspired creature can roll a d6 and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. This uses 1 charge from the crown. It has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 223</text>		<roll>1d3</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Mask of the Dragon Queen</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>unique (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>Individually, the five dragon masks resemble the dragons they are named for. When two or more of the dragon masks are assembled, however, they transform magically into the Mask of the Dragon Queen. Each mask shrinks to become the modeled head of a chromatic dragon, appearing to roar its devotion to Tiamat where all the masks brought together are arranged crown-like on the wearer's head. Below the five masks, a new mask shapes itself, granting the wearer a draconic visage that covers the face, neck, and shoulders.</text>		<text>	While you are attuned to and wear this mask, you can have any of the properties from any one mask. Additionally, you gain the Damage Absorption from each of the five dragon masks, and you gain five uses of the Legendary Resistance property.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: The Rise of Tiamat p. 94</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Mirror of the Past</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare</detail>		<weight>0.5</weight>		<text>The holder of this platinum hand mirror can learn something about the history of a specific object or creature by taking an action to gaze into the mirror and think of the target. Instead of the holder's reflection, the mirror presents scenes from the target's past. Information conveyed is accurate, but it is random and cryptic, and presented in no particular order. Once it is activated, the mirror gives its information for 1 minute or less, then returns to normal. It can't be used again until the next dawn.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Navigation Orb</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A navigation orb is a hollow, 7-foot-diameter sphere of thin, polished mithral with a large skye (cloud) rune embossed on its outer surface. The orb levitates 10 feet above the ground and is keyed to a particular cloud castle, allowing you to control that castle's altitude and movement while the orb is inside the castle. If the orb is destroyed or removed from its castle, the castle's altitude and location remain fixed until the orb is returned or replaced. </text>		<text>	As an action, you can cause one of the following effects to occur if you are touching the orb: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; The castle moves at a speed of 1 mph in a straight line, in a direction of your choice, until the castle stops or is made to stop, or until another action is used to change its direction. If this movement brings the castle into contact with the ground , the castle lands gently. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; The castle, if it is moving, comes to a gradual stop. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; The castle makes a slow, 90-degree turn clockwise or counterclockwise (turning a northerly view into a westerly view, for example). The castle can turn while it is moving in a straight line. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>	Any creature touching the orb knows the altitude of the base of the castle above the ground or water below it.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 237</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Night Caller</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This whistle is carved from transparent crystal, and it resembles a tiny dragon curled up like a snail. The name Night Caller is etched on the whistle in Dwarvish runes. If a character succeeds on a DC 20 Intelligence (Arcana or History) check, the character recalls lore that says the duergar made several such whistles for various groups in an age past. </text>		<text>	If you blow the whistle in darkness or under the night sky, it allows you to cast the animate dead spell. The target can be affected through up to 10 feet of soft earth or similar material, and if it is, it takes 1 minute to claw its way to the surface to serve you. Once the whistle has animated an undead creature, it can't do so again until 7 days have passed. </text>		<text>	Once every 24 hours, you can blow the whistle to reassert control over one or two creatures you animated with it.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 228</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Opal of the Ild Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This triangular fire opal measures about three inches on each side and is half an inch thick. The ild (fire) rune shimmers within its core, causing it to be slightly warm to the touch. The opal has the following properties, which work only while it's on your person. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Ignite: As an action, you can ignite an object within 10 feet of you. The object must be flammable, and the fire starts in a circle no larger than 1 foot in diameter. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Fire's Friend: You have resistance to cold damage. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Fire Tamer: As an action, you can extinguish any open flame within 10 feet of you. You choose how much fire to extinguish in that radius. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Gift of Flame: You can transfer the opal's magic to a nonmagical item &#8212; a weapon or a suit of armor &#8212; by tracing the ild rune there with your finger. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the two items to be within 5 feet of each other. At the end, the opal is destroyed, and the rune appears in red on the chosen item, which gains a benefit based on its form: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Weapon: The weapon is now an uncommon magic weapon. It deals an extra 1d6 fire damage to any target it hits. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Armor: The armor is now a rare magic item that requires attunement. You have resistance to cold damage while wearing the armor.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 237</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Orb of the Stein Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This orb of granite is about the size of an adult human's fist. The stein (stone) rune appears on it in the form of crystalline veins that run across the surface. The orb has the following properties, which work only while it's on your person. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Indomitable Stand: As an action, you can channel the orb's magic to hold your ground. For the next minute or until you move any distance, you have advantage on all checks and saving throws to resist effects that force you to move. In addition, any enemy that moves to a space within 10 feet of you must succeed on a DC 12 Strength saving throw or be unable to move any farther this turn. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Stone Soul: You can't be petrified. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Earthen Step: You can cast meld into stone as a bonus action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Gift of Stone: You can transfer the orb's magic to a nonmagical item &#8212; a shield or a pair of boots &#8212; by tracing the stein rune there with your finger. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the two items to be within 5 feet of each other. At the end, the orb is destroyed, and the rune appears in silver on the chosen item, which gains a benefit based on its form: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Shield: The shield is now a rare magic item that requires attunement. While you wield it, you have resistance to all damage dealt by ranged weapon attacks. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Boots: The pair of boots is now an uncommon magic item that requires attunement. While you wear the boots, you have advantage on Strength saving throws, and you can use your reaction to avoid being knocked prone.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 237</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Pennant of the Vind Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This blue pennant is crafted from silk and is five feet long and whips about as if buffeted by a wind. The vind (wind) rune appears on its surface, looking almost like a cloud. The pennant has the following properties, which work only while it's on your person.</text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Wind Step: As an action, you fly up to 20 feet. If you don't land at the end of this flight, you fall unless you have another means of staying aloft. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Comforting Wind: You can't suffocate. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Wind's Grasp; As a reaction when you fall, you can cause yourself to take no damage from the fall. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Wind Walker: While you are attuned to this rune, you can cast levitate as a bonus action. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Gift of Wind: You can transfer the pennant's magic to a nonmagical item &#8212; a suit of armor, a pair of boots, or a cloak &#8212; by tracing the vind rune there with your finger. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the two items to be within 5 feet of each other. At the end, the pennant is destroyed, and the rune appears in silver on the chosen item, which gains a benefit based on its form: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Armor: The armor is now an uncommon magic item that requires attunement. You gain a bonus to speed of 5 feet while you wear the armor, and if it normally imposes disadvantage on Stealth checks, it no longer does so. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Boots/Cloak: The pair of boots or cloak is now a rare magic item that requires attunement. While wearing the item, you can convert up to 20 feet of your movement on each of your turns into flight. If you don't land at the end of this flight, you fall unless you have another means of staying aloft . You can also cast feather fall once from the item, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a short or long rest.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 237</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Piwafwi</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This dark spider-silk cloak is made by drow. It is a cloak of elvenkind: while you wear this cloak with its hood up, Wisdom (Perception) checks made to see you have disadvantage. and you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide, as the cloak's color shifts to camouflage you. Pulling the hood up or down requires an action. It loses its magic if exposed to sunlight for 1 hour without interruption.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Piwafwi of Fire Resistance</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This dark spider-silk cloak is made by drow. It is a cloak of elvenkind: while you wear this cloak with its hood up, Wisdom (Perception) checks made to see you have disadvantage. and you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide, as the cloak's color shifts to camouflage you. Pulling the hood up or down requires an action. It also grants resistance to fire damage while you wear it.  It loses its magic if exposed to sunlight for 1 hour without interruption.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 222</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Red Dragon Mask</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This mask of glossy crimson has swept-back horns and spiked cheek ridges. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Damage Absorption: You have resistance against fire damage. If you already have resistance to fire damage from another source, you instead have immunity to fire damage. If you already have immunity to fire damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to fire damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Red Dragons.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Fire: If you deal fire damage to a creature or flammable object, it starts burning. At the start of each of its turns, a creature burning in this way takes 1d6 fire damage. A creature that can reach the burning target can use an action to extinguish the fire.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement p. 4</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Robe of Serpents</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A robe of serpents is a stylish silk garment that is popular among wealthy nobles and retired assassins. The robe is emblazoned with 1d4 + 3 stylized serpents, all brightly colored. </text>		<text>	As a bonus action on your turn, you can transform one of the robe's serpents into a giant poisonous snake. The snake instantly falls from the robe, slithers into an unoccupied space next to you, and acts on your initiative count. The snake can tell friendly creatures from hostile ones and attacks the latter. The snake disappears in a harmless puff of smoke after 1 hour, when it drops to 0 hit points, or when you dismiss it (no action required). Once detached, a snake can't return to the robe. When all of the robe's snakes have detached, the robe becomes a nonmagical garment.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 238</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Robe of Summer</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This elegant garment is made from fine cloth in hues of red, orange, and gold. While you wear the robe, you have resistance to cold damage. In addition, you are comfortable as if the temperature were that of a balmy day, so you suffer no ill effects from the weather's temperature extremes.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Rod of the Vonindod</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>The fire giant duke Zalto hired a wizard to craft several of these adamantine rods. Each measures 4 feet long, weighs 100 pounds, and is sized to fit comfortably in a fire giant's hand. The rod has two prongs at one end and a molded handle grip on the opposite end. </text>		<text>	The rod has 10 charges and regains 1d6 + 4 of its expended charges daily at dawn. As an action, you can grasp it by the handle and expend 1 charge to cast the locate object spell from it. When the rod is used to detect objects made of adamantine, such as fragments of the Vonindod construct, its range increases to 10 miles.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 238</text>		<roll>1d6+4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Shard of the Ise Rune</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This shard of ice is long and slender, roughly the size of a dagger. The ise (ice) rune glows within it. The shard has the following properties, which work only while it's on your person. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Frigid Touch: As an action, you can touch a body of water and freeze the water in a 10-foot-radius sphere around the spot you touched. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Frost Friend: You have resistance to fire damage. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Icy Mantle: As an action, you can touch yourself or another creature with water on your finger. The water creates an icy mantle of protection. The next time within the next minute that the target takes bludgeoning, slashing, or piercing damage, that damage is reduced to 0, and the mantle is destroyed. Once you use this property, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Winter's Howl: As an action, you can cast sleet storm (spell save DC 17). You regain this ability after you finish a short or long rest. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Gift of Frost. You can transfer the shard's magic to a nonmagical item &#8212; a cloak or a pair of boots &#8212; by tracing the ise rune there with your finger. The transfer takes 8 hours of work that requires the two items to be within 5 feet of each other. At the end, the shard is destroyed, and the rune appears in blue on the chosen item, which gains a benefit based on its form: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Cloak: The cloak is now a rare magic item that requires attunement. While wearing it, you have resistance to fire damage, and you have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made while in snowy terrain. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Boots: The pair of boots is now a rare magic item that requires attunement. While wearing it, you ignore difficult terrain while walking, and you can walk on water.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 238</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Amber</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	An amber spell gem can store up to 4th level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 15 and an attack bonus of +9.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Bloodstone</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A bloodstone spell gem can store up to 3rd level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 15 and an attack bonus of +7.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Diamond</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A diamond spell gem can store up to 9th level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 19 and an attack bonus of +11.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Jade</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A jade spell gem can store up to 5th level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 17 and an attack bonus of +9.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Lapis Lazuli</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A lapis lazuli spell gem can store up to 1st level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 13 and an attack bonus of +5.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Obsidian</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	An obsidian spell gem can store cantrips. Cantrips cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 13 and an attack bonus of +5.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Quartz</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A quartz spell gem can store up to 2nd level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 13 and an attack bonus of +5.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Ruby</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A ruby spell gem can store up to 8th level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 18 and an attack bonus of +10.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Star Ruby</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A star ruby spell gem can store up to 7th level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 18 and an attack bonus of +10.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Spell Gem, Topaz</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>very rare (Attunement Optional)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A spell gem can contain one spell from any class's spell list. You become aware of the spell when you learn the gem's properties. While holding the gem, you can cast the spell from it as an action if you know the spell or if the spell is on your class's spell list. Doing so doesn't require any components, and doesn't require attunement. The spell then disappears from the gem.</text>		<text>	A topaz spell gem can store up to 6th level spells. Spells cast from the spell gem have a save DC of 17 and an attack bonus of +10.</text>		<text>	You can imbue the gem with a spell if you're attuned to it and it's empty. To do so, you cast the spell while holding the gem. The spell is stored in the gem instead of having any effect. Casting the spell must require either 1 action or 1 minute or longer, and the spell's level must be no higher than the gem's maximum. IF the spell belongs to the school of abjuration and requires material components that are consumed, you must provide them, but they can be worth half as much as normal.</text>		<text>	Once imbued with a spell, the gem can't be imbued again until the next dawn.</text>		<text>	Deep gnomes created these magic gemstones and keep the creation process a secret.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Stone of Ill Luck</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon, cursed (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This polished agate appears to be a stone of good luck to anyone who tries to identify it, and it confers that item's property while on your person. </text>		<text>Curse: This item is cursed. While it is on your person, you take a -2 penalty to ability checks and saving throws. Until the curse is discovered, the DM secretly applies this penalty, assuming you are adding the item's bonus. You are unwilling to part with the stone until the curse is broken with remove curse or similar magic.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Stonespeaker Crystal</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>Created by the stone giant librarians of Gravenhollow, this nineteen-inch-long shard of quartz grants you advantage on Intelligence (investigation) checks while it is on your person.</text>		<text>	The crystal has 10 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend some of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it: speak with animals (2 charges), speak with dead (4 charges), or speak with plants (3 charges).</text>		<text>	When you cast a divination spell, you can use the crystal in place of one material component that would normally be consumed by the spell, at a cost of 1 charge per level of the spell. The crystal is not consumed when used in this way.</text>		<text>	The crystal regains 1d6+4 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the crystal's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the crystal vanishes, lost forever.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>		<roll>1d6+4</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Weird Tank</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>A weird tank is a ten-gallon tank of blown glass and sculpted bronze with a backpack-like carrying harness fashioned from tough leather. A water weird (see the Monster Manual for statistics) is contained within the tank. While wearing the tank, you can use an action to open it, allowing the water weird to emerge. The water weird acts immediately after you in the initiative order, and it is bound to the tank.</text>		<text>	You can command the water weird telepathically (no action required) while you wear the tank. You can close the tank as an action only if you have first commanded the water weird to retract into it or if the water weird is dead.</text>		<text>	If the water weird is killed, the tank loses its magical containment property until it spends at least 24 hours inside an elemental water node. When the tank is recharged, a new water weird forms inside it.</text>		<text>	The tank has AC 15, 50 hit points, vulnerability to bludgeoning damage, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing the tank to 0 hit points destroys it and the water weird contained within it.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>White Dragon Mask</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>legendary (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This gleaming mask is white with highlights of pale blue and is topped by a spined crest. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Damage Absorption: You have resistance against cold damage. If you already have resistance to cold damage from another source, you instead have immunity to cold damage. If you already have immunity to cold damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to cold damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against White Dragons.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>		<text>	</text>		<text>	Winter's Fury: While your current hit points are equal to or less than half your hit point maximum, you deal an extra 1d8 cold damage with your melee attacks.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement p. 4</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Wingwear</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>This snug uniform has symbols of air stitched into it and leathery flaps that stretch along the arms, waist, and legs to create wings for gliding. A suit of wingwear has 3 charges. While you wear the suit, you can use a bonus action and expend 1 charge to gain a flying speed of 30 feet until you land. At the end of each of your turns, your altitude drops by 5 feet. Your altitude drops instantly to 0 feet at the end of your turn if you didn't fly at least 30 feet horizontally on that turn. When your altitude drops to 0 feet, you land (or fall), and you must expend another charge to use the suit again.</text>		<text>	The suit regains all of its expended charges after spending at least 1 hour in an elemental air node.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse p. 223</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Wyrmskull Throne</name>		<type>W</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>artifact</detail>		<weight></weight>		<text>Built by dwarven gods and entrusted to the rulers of Shanatar, an ancient dwarven empire, the Wyrmskull Throne was a symbol of dwarven power and pride for ages untold. The throne hovers a foot off the ground and is a massive thing made of polished obsidian with oversized feet &#8212; the impaled skulls of four ancient blue dragons. Runes glisten in the carved obsidian, winking to life with blue energy when the throne's powers are activated. </text>		<text>	After the fall of Shanatar, the Wyrmskull Throne fell into the clutches of less honorable creatures. A band of adventurers wrested the throne from the aquatic elf tyrant Gantar Kraok and sold it to the storm giant Neri for a considerable fortune. Neri had the throne magically enlarged and gave it to her husband, King Hekaton, as a gift, along with one of the Ruling Scepters of Shanatar, which she had found in a wreck at the bottom of the Trackless Sea. Only a creature attuned to a Ruling Scepter and in possession of it can harness the powers of the Wyrmskull Throne, which has become the centerpiece of King Hekaton's throne room in the undersea citadel of Maelstrom. Fear of the throne's power has helped prevent evil giants from challenging or threatening Hekaton's leadership. </text>		<text>	Any creature not attuned to a Ruling Scepter who sits on the throne is paralyzed and encased in a magical force field. While encased, the creature can't be touched or moved from the throne. Touching a Ruling Scepter to the force field dispels the field, though the creature remains paralyzed until it is separated from the throne. </text>		<text>	Any creature seated on the throne can hear faint whispers in Draconic &#8212; the whisperings of the four blue dragons whose skulls adorn the throne. Although powerless, these spirits try to influence the decisions of the throne's master. </text>		<text>	Properties of the Throne: The throne has 9 charges and regains all expended charges daily at dawn. A creature that sits on the throne while attuned to a Ruling Scepter in its possession can harness the throne's properties, which are as follows: </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; The throne gains a flying speed of 30 feet and can hover and flies where the creature wills. This property doesn't expend any charges. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; Both the throne and the creature sitting on it can move through earth and stone without disturbing the material they move through. This property doesn't expend any charges. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; As an action, the creature can expend 1 charge to cast lightning bolt (spell save DC 19) from the throne. The spell is cast as though using a 9th-level spell slot and deals 49 (14d6) lightning damage. The bolt discharges from the mouth of one of the throne's blue dragon skulls. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; As an action, the creature can expend 2 charges to cast the globe of invulnerability spell from the throne. The globe encloses both the creature and the throne. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>&#8226; As an action, the creature can expend 3 charges to create a spectral image of an ancient blue dragon that surrounds both it and the throne. The spectral dragon lasts for 1 minute. At the end of each of the creature's turns, the spectral dragon makes one bite attack and two claw attacks against targets of the creature's choice. These attacks have the same attack bonus, reach, and damage as an ancient blue dragon's bite and claw attacks. </text>		<text>	 </text>		<text>Destroying the Throne: The Wyrmskull Throne can be destroyed by breaking at least five Ruling Scepters of Shanatar simultaneously on it. This fact has never been recorded or sung of among the dwarves or any bards or storytellers, and it can't be discovered with an ability check. Characters who want to destroy the throne must go on a quest to learn the method for doing so. The throne's destruction triggers an explosion, as shards of obsidian fly out in all directions. Each creature and object within a 30-foot-radius sphere centered on the throne must succeed on a DC 21 Dexterity saving throw, taking 70 (20d6) slashing damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Storm King's Thunder, p. 239</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Wand of Entangle</name>		<type>WD</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>uncommon (requires attunement by a spellcaster)</detail>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>This wand has 7 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 1 of its charges to cast the entangle spell (save DC 13) from it. </text>		<text>	The wand regains 1d6+1 expended charges daily at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the wand crumbles into ashes and is destroyed.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Tales from the Yawning Portal, p. 229</text>		<roll>1d6+1</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Wand of Viscid Globs</name>		<type>WD</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>Crafted by the drow, this slim black wand has 7 charges. While holding it, you can use an action to expend 1 of its charges to cause a small glob of viscous material to launch from the tip at one creature within 60 feet of you. Make a ranged attack roll against the target, with a bonus equal to your spellcasting modifier (or your Intelligence modifier, if you don't have a spellcasting modifier) plus your proficiency bonus. On a hit, the glob expands and dries on the target, which is restrained for 1 hour. After that time, the viscous material cracks and falls away.</text>		<text>	Applying a pint or more of alcohol to the restrained creature dissolves the glob instantly, as does the application of oil of etherealness or universal solvent. The glob also dissolves instantly if exposed to sunlight. No other nonmagical process can remove the viscous material until it deteriorates on its own.</text>		<text>	The wand regains 1d6 + 1 expended charges daily at midnight. If you expend the wands last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the wand melts into harmless slime and is destroyed.</text>		<text>	A wand of viscid globs is destroyed if exposed to sunlight for 1 hour without interruption.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Out of the Abyss, p. 223</text>		<roll>1d6+1</roll>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Wand of Winter</name>		<type>WD</type>		<magic>1</magic>		<detail>rare (requires attunement)</detail>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>This wand looks and feels like an icicle. You must be attuned to the want to use it.</text>		<text>	The wand has 7 charges, which are used to fuel the spells within it. With the wand in hand, you can use your action to cast one of the following spells from the wand, even if you are incapable of casting spells: ray of frost (no charges, or 1 charge to cast at 5th level; +5 to hit with ranged spell attack), sleet storm (3 charges; spell save DC 15), or ice storm (4 charges; spell save DC 15). No components are required. The wand regains 1d6+1 expended charges each day at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll a d20. On a 20, the wand melts away, forever destroyed.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen p. 94</text>		<roll>1d6+1</roll>	</item>
</compendium>
